<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kubernetes on Milind&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kubernetes on Milind&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 18:09:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://milindchawre.github.io/site/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Excluding Specific Logs From a Particular Pod in Fluentd</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/micro/excluding-specific-logs-from-a-particular-pod-in-fluentd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 18:09:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/micro/excluding-specific-logs-from-a-particular-pod-in-fluentd/</guid>
      <description>Problem: I want to exclude these noisy logs coming from activemq pod.
kubernetes-cluster-logging $ kubectl logs activemq-79bd55f9c-jdtqf --tail 10 -fWARN | Transport Connection to: tcp://172.29.108.66:37302 failed: java.io.EOFExceptionWARN | Transport Connection to: tcp://172.29.108.66:37366 failed: java.io.EOFExceptionWARN | Transport Connection to: tcp://172.29.108.66:37518 failed: java.io.EOFExceptionWARN | Transport Connection to: tcp://172.29.108.66:37582 failed: java.io.EOFExceptionSolution:  Create regex pattern for your log line that need to be excluded. Use kubernetes_metadata filter to enrich logs with kubernetes metadata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips to ace in CKA and CKAD exam</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/tips-to-ace-in-cka-and-ckad-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:00:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/tips-to-ace-in-cka-and-ckad-exam/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally featured as a guide in civo cloud community.
        CKAD and CKA Certificate    I recently passed both CKA and CKAD exams, scoring 98% and 96% respectively. In this blog, I want to share my overall experience and tips to crack these exams.
What is CKA? CKA is the Certified Kubernetes Administrator certification, which focuses on administrative skills of managing, troubleshooting and operating a kubernetes cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sloop: a Tool to Visualize the History of Kubernetes Resources</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/sloop-a-tool-to-visualize-the-history-of-kubernetes-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 16:00:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/sloop-a-tool-to-visualize-the-history-of-kubernetes-resources/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally featured as a guide in civo cloud community.
Introducing Sloop Sloop is an open source tool to visualize history of all resources in your kubernetes cluster. It was built by salesforce.
Problem: Keeping track of events in your clusters Workloads running in Kubernetes cluster are dynamic in nature. The pods, replicas, deployments in your cluster keeps going on and off over the period of time due to their ephemeral nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K3s Upgrade: A Simplified Guide</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/k3s-upgrade-a-simplified-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 23:03:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/k3s-upgrade-a-simplified-guide/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally featured as a guide in kubezilla community.
Introduction K3s is a lightweight Kubernetes distribution which runs with a very small footprint and is a suitable candidate for edge computing. K3s is capable of nearly everything k8s can do. It is just a more lightweight version. It is the ONLY certified Kubernetes distribution built for IoT &amp;amp; Edge computing. It is a highly available, certified Kubernetes distribution designed for production workloads in unattended, resource-constrained, remote locations or inside IoT appliances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop and Test Your Code Directly in Kubernetes Using Okteto</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/develop-and-test-your-code-directly-in-kubernetes-using-okteto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 23:54:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/develop-and-test-your-code-directly-in-kubernetes-using-okteto/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally featured as a guide in civo cloud community.
Introduction Okteto is an open source tool to develop and test your code directly in Kubernetes. In this guide will walk you through how to develop Java application on a Kubernetes cluster using Okteto.
Defining the Problem Systems based on microservice architecture have many advantages like scalability, resilience, fault tolerance and so on. But they are also harder to setup locally as a development environment due to their very nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairwinds Goldilocks : Kubernetes Resource Recommendation Tool</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/fairwinds-goldilocks-kubernetes-resource-recommendation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 20:45:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/fairwinds-goldilocks-kubernetes-resource-recommendation-tool/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally featured as a guide in civo cloud community.
Fairwinds Goldilocks is an open source tool that recommends the right settings for resource requests and limits on kubernetes workloads. It was built by Fairwinds (formerly ReactiveOps).
Problem It is said that good fences make good neighbors, it&amp;rsquo;s true for applications too. Applications were typically designed to run standalone in a machine and use all of the resources at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Polaris on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/setting-up-polaris-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 18:01:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://milindchawre.github.io/site/blog/setting-up-polaris-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>This blog was originally featured as a guide in civo cloud community.
Polaris is an open-source project that looks for configuration issues in kubernetes that can affect stability, reliability, scalability, and security. It was built by Fairwinds (formerly ReactiveOps).
Problem Creating cluster is easy, but running it at scale with stability and security is hard. We have seen this often: a small mistake in deployment configuration can later result in bigger issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
